Alexander Matyushentsev

Senior Web Developer

email: amatyushentsev@gmail.com

phone: +1 (201) 688-0079

web: http://amatyushentsev.com

linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/in/amatyushentsev/

github: https://github.com/alexmt

SUMMARY

I'm a software engineer, currently working in Mountain View, California. I have around eight years of experience in commercial software development using various programming languages and platforms. My primary skill is web application development using Java on server side but also have a strong background in .NET/C#. I'm an enthusiast of continuous integration, and agile environments. I like working on scalability, performance, design, and great user experiences.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages Java, C#, JavaScript, SQL and basic knowledge of C/C++, Kotlin, Groovy, Python

Java Core Java, Servlets, JSP, JAX-RS, Spring, Guice

.Net ASP.NET MVC, WFC, .Net Remoting, Winforms, ADO.NET

Client Side AngularJS, GWT, jQuery, jQuery UI, ExtJS

Testing WebDriver, Jasmine, Mockito, JUnit, NUnit, MSTest, Moq

Databases MS SQL, MySQL

Dev Tools Maven, Gradle, Grunt, NodeJS, Eclipse, Intellij Idea, Visual Studio, Git, TF:

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

Master's Degree Orenburg State University, Information Technology Faculty Computing machinery, complex, systems and network

Certifications MCPD (MCP transcript id: 921335; access code: 32165487) available at https://mcp.microsoft.com/authenticate/validatemcp.aspx

OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS

Photomover: Allows to manage photos in G+, Flickr etc.

Environment: Kotlin, JVM, Jetty, JAX-RS, AnguarJS, CouchDb, Grunt, Gradle, Heroku

Home page: http://photomover.herokuapp.com/ Sources: https://github.com/alexmt/photomover

Atom.IO Translator plugin: A tool to translate text in Atom.io via Microsoft Translator API.

Environment: Coffeescript, LESS, NodeJS

Home page: https://atom.io/packages/translator

Sources: https://github.com/alexmt/atom-translator

Atom.IO Koltin Language plugin: Adds syntax highlighting to Kotlin files in Atom.

Environment: Coffeescript, NodeJS

Home page: https://atom.io/packages/language-kotlin
Sources: https://github.com/alexmt/atom-kotlin-language

CAREER HISTORY

Contractor Senior Java Developer at Google

2011 - Present, EPAM Systems, Mountain View, C

DoubleClick Data Platform (DDP) API: centralized hub for the origination and sharing of 1st party data and licensing of 3rd-party data. DDP API is taking care of distribution of that information across various Google advertising products.

Environment: Java, Google F1 database, Stubby RPC, protocol buffers, Guice, Google cloud **Responsibilities:**

- Participated in development of new API features starting from analyzing requirements to integration tests.
- Configured build and release process.

DoubleClick Data Platform (DDP) UI: an interactive Web application which allows data providers to browse, create and manage data segments, sell segments with to advertisers and manage these shares.

Environment: Java, GWT, Servlets, Stubby RPC, protocol buffers, Gin **Responsibilities:**

- Analyzed product requirements, designed and created UI mock-ups, implemented web UI using GWT framework.
- Implemented automated integration tests using WebDriver framework.
- Worked on continuous integration, build and release configuration.

DCLK QPS: a web service which allows to set up and enforce publisher apps load management rules.

Environment: Java, Spring, Jetty, JDBC, HSQLDB, MySql **Responsibilities:**

- Designed application architecture and implemented core functionality.
- Worked on DCLK QPS integration with my DFP6 suite products.

Senior .Net Developer

2011, Paladyne Systems, Inc., St. Petersburg, Russi

Report Manager: web application which allows fund administrators to configure and maintain client portals providing access to information on investments to the funds' clients. Works as a single location for viewing all fund reports existing in Paladyne Suite.

Environment: ASP.NET WebForms, Silverlight 4.0, ExtJS 3.3, HTML, CSS, WCF, MS SQL Server 2008, VS 2010, IIS7.0, TFS2010

Responsibilities:

- Developed GUI using Silverlight 4.0 and ExtJS 3.3 framework.
- Implemented web services using WCF.
- Designed MS SQL database schema.
- Configured MSBuild project.

Senior .Net Developer

2010, Brady PLC Norway AS, St. Petersburg, Russi

Web Sales Manager: a web application based on ASP.NET MVC framework. Web Sales Manager provides the option pricing functions for the European energy markets.

Environment: ASP.NET MVC 2.0, C#, NHibernate 3.0, JavaScript, jQuery, jQuery UI, HTML, CSS, MS SQL Server 2008, Visual Studio

Responsibilities:

- Design application architecture.
- Implemented persistent layer using NHibernate 3.0.

- Developed GUI using ASP.NET MVC 2.0 and jQuery UI.
- Prepared design documents, estimation.
- Prepared and executed unit tests using NUnit framework.

Senior .Net Developer

2007 - 2010, VIACode, St. Petersburg, Russi

CT TyMetrix 360°: is an integrated platform combining e-Billing, matter management, document management, financial reporting, budgeting and forecasting.

Environment: ASP.NET WebForms, C#, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MS SQL Server 2008, Visual Studio 2008, XML, LINQ, IIS, Team Foundation Server 2008

Responsibilities:

- Developed GUI using ASP.NET WebForms.
- Developed user defined functions, stored procedures and views using T-SQL.
- Implemented distributed system using WCF services.
- Participated in development of Ajax framework.
- Prepared analysis, design documents, estimation, for different components and functional modules required by the system.
- Prepared and executed unit tests using MSTest framework.
- Migrated legacy ASP.NET solution to MVC.
- Developed unit testing standards and guidelines for the company.

.Net Developer

2006 - 2007, KomTelSvjaz LLC, Orenburg, Russia

Internal geoinformation system: an interactive map providing ability to view and edit geographic information, including streets, buildings.

Environment: WinForms, C#, MS SQL Server 2005, Visual Studio 2005, Visual SourceSafe **Responsibilities:**

- Implemented GUI for numerous modules using C#.
- Designed core components and recyclable assemblies.
- Created tables and views using T-SQL.
- Implemented unit tests with using of NUnit framework.

Network equipment monitoring system: a distributed system responsible for real-time monitoring for servers (Windows, UNIX, Linux) and any other device on network.

Environment: WinForms, Infragistics Components, C#, .Net Remoting, XML, SNMP, Visual Studio 2005. Visual SourceSafe

Responsibilities:

- Designed and developed application using.
- Creating tables and views using SQL.
- Implemented monitoring system engine using SNMP protocol.
- Unit testing with NUnit framework.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.